and today I want to show you how you can
secure your API keys for free in less
than 5 minutes when we build a project
and we use a third-party API most of the
time they give us an API key so we can
use their services the thing is that if
you don't have a server and you're
building a web application or a mobile
application you might end up putting
those API keys on the code that is going
to go to the browser or to the phone of
the user which means that someone with a
little bit of technical skills can
inspect your code or look at the network
call and extract your API Keys the only
place where your API keys will be
protected is on your server but making
and managing a server just to protect a
couple of API Keys is a lot of effort
enter cloudflare workers cluster workers
is the easiest and fastest way I found
of deploying code to the cloud all we
have to do is write a JavaScript or
typescript function run one command and
boom the code will be deployed on class
first Network and we will get a URL to
run it even though it might look like it
this video isn't sponsored by cluster I
just really like their workers product
and it has become my go-to service when
I need to build an API or run some code
on the cloud they actually have all
their cool products like R2 for cheap
file storage the one a serverless SQL
database Chrome jobs a key value
database and more let me know in the
comments if you would like me to make
tutorials about those products as well
for now let's get started protecting our
case with cloudstar workers keep in mind
that cluster workers is free you get a
hundred thousand requests per day at no
cost and after that you will pay 15
cents per million requests after
creating a cluster account in your
console you will run npm install GE
Wrangler after that from your console
you will run Wrangler login which will
log in our console with cloudstar after
that we are going to run Wrangler init
Keys Dash y to create a keys folder
after we open the keys folder we will
find a node.js project with an index.ts
file that contains the code of our
function all this code does for now is
to say hello world when somebody goes to
the URL to test it just run Wrangler Dev
on the console and you will get a URL
that you can open in your browser where
you will see Hello work so now let's
pretend that we are building an app that
is using the movie database API and that
is the API key we want to protect what
we want to do is we want to mirror the
same structure of the movie database API
which means that we will still be able
to read the API documentation but
instead of sending requests directly to
the movie database API we are going to
send them to our worker and our worker
will forward the request lost the API
key to note which path the user is going
we will extract the path name of the URL
as well as the search parameter so if
you have a request like this one the
best thing is going to be slash movie
slash popular and the search programs
will be the page equals to what we want
to do next is to relay the path name and
the search parameters to the actual the
movie database API plus our API key next
step is to actually fetch that URL we
just created and get the Json out of the
response and to finish up we're going to
take that Json we will stringify it and
send it in our response as Json and now
we can go to slash movie slash popular
in our browser and that request will be
forwarded to the movie database API
server and we will get the resulting
data without having to rebuild our API
key to enable fetch to that API from our
browser we need to enable course which
we can do just by sending the correct
headers now all we have to do is run
Wrangler publish in our console and
after waiting for a bit we will get the
URL where our worker will leave and
that's it we can now use that URL which
in my case is keys that Nomad colors
that workers that Dev in our websites
and apps that's it for this video thank
you for watching I hope you found it
useful let me know in the comments what
do you think about cluster workers and
let me know you would like to see more
videos about other Cloud products and
don't forget that if you want to learn
things like JavaScript python react
react native gold Dart flutter among
many others for absolutely free all you
have to do is click the link below to
join any of our many free courses that
you can take right now for absolutely
free with me click on the link below and
I will see you there
see you on the next one bye
thank you
[Music]